<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nodev on I Prefer Jim</title>
    <link>https://www.ipreferjim.com/tags/nodev/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nodev on I Prefer Jim</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2010 04:26:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ipreferjim.com/tags/nodev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tip for Writers and Novelists: Use Subversion to track changes in your work!</title>
      <link>https://www.ipreferjim.com/2010/11/tip-for-writers-and-novelists-use-subversion-to-track-changes-in-your-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2010 04:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ipreferjim.com/2010/11/tip-for-writers-and-novelists-use-subversion-to-track-changes-in-your-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a developer, I take some things like version control for granted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I suggested version control to my wife to make it easier for her to compare her current revisions with earlier revisions.  Currently, when she wants to make a new revision, she creates a new file with a different filename.  This doesn’t give her to Word comparing or change tracking.  So, if she deleted a paragraph two, three, or twenty revisions ago, she could easily go back to a draft containing the paragraph and retrieve the text or compare against the current revision.  It would even be possible to check out the earlier revision!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of change tracking, a subversion repository offers a complete backup of documents.  This would be excellent for someone who is worried about losing their documents.  For instance, you can create a subversion repository on an external hard drive and you’ll never lose anything earlier than your last check-in.  Granted, you have to adopt the version control process, but the benefits greatly outweigh the possible headaches of having no sort of version control or revision history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For any writers who may stumble across my site, this post will walk you through setting up a local subversion repository for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Required Download: &lt;a title=&#34;Download ToroiseSVN&#34; href=&#34;http://tortoisesvn.net/downloads&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TortoiseSVN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My version of TortoiseSVN is 1.6.6.  Although your version may be slightly different than the screenshots, the overall steps should remain the same.  After installing TortoiseSVN, be sure to reboot your computer to make sure the svn caching mechanism is working. Then, continue reading…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>